# Ramiro Garcia

### **Contact**

• E-Mail: hire-me@ramirogarcia.xyz

• LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/garcia-ramiro

• X: @ranemirusG

• GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/ranemirusG">https://github.com/ranemirusG</a>

#### **About**

My involvement with technology stems from exploring various disciplines.

In 8 years as an entrepreneur, I discovered the challenges of security in organizations and, related to this, I got interested in information flows and privacy.

I've been programming for several years. In 2022 I decided to make my way into cybersecurity specialization.

# **Experience**

# 2016-2023 — <u>Lecop Central</u>

I co-founded a company from scratch, which culminated in its successful sale in 2023.

A B2B service designed to streamline the supply of office supplies through a unified channel and a program aimed at employee well-being and retention goals, eliminating the need to manage multiple suppliers.

Throughout these years, I tested my ability to adapt to uncertain and risky scenarios. I was responsible for the design and implementation of every aspect of the organization, including:

- General management of the company and development of solutions for +300 clients in Argentina.
- Administration and operational direction of a team of +10 people.
- Process automation in the supply chain and creation of a customized management system.

#### 2012-2016 — Otros

Previously, I have explored various paths, including roles in administrative and sales areas, teaching, as well as some microenterprises.

#### Skills

# Languages

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Professional)
- Portuguese (Professional)

# **Programming**

Currently, I am focusing on **c**++, networking, and computer fundamentals. Additionally, I have growing proficiency in Pentesting, Antimalware Analysis, and Threat Intelligence.

I use Python, Bash, and Powershell as daily drivers for multipurpose scripting.

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, macOS.

I also have general knowledge of Databases, Go, Lisp, Lua, Perl, PHP, Ruby, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS.

I learn quickly, so I am open to opportunities regardless of the stack of technologies or frameworks used.

# **Projects**

- Enhancing skill sets in <u>TryHackMe</u> (view my profile)
- Volunteer in the cybersecurity subcommittee for the <u>5th People's Health Assembly</u> PHA5
- Collaborated on documentation for the DVWA repository
- Static websites, web scrapers, CRM, and Management Systems.
- I am passionate about text editors and text operations. My favorite editor is **Vim**, and I'm involved in the community.

# **Education & Background**

My diverse interests have led me through various educational experiences, and despite not having completed any university degree, I owe much to these experiences.

I am self-taught in many subjects, consider myself a good reader, and adept at finding resources. I have also learned from various courses and, most importantly, from conversations with *makers* and experts.

In the context of this presentation, I would like to highlight:

- **2024 (currently)** Burp Suite Certified Practitioner (BSCP) by <u>Portswigger</u>
- 2024 Curso de ciberseguridad para microempresas y autónomos del sector Salud by <u>INCIBE</u>
- 2023 Fundamentals of Hacking and Defense by **Ekoparty**
- **2023** ISC2 CC by <u>ISC2</u>
- 2022 Ecosistema Crypto & Defi 101 by Defy Education
- 2016-2019 Licenciatura en Sociología; UBA (Argentina)
- 2009-2014 Licenciatura en Música; UNLP (Argentina)